guys this is implicit differentiation
it's saying find dydx when x squared
minus x y equals 25. step one we're
going to take the derivative of both
sides so what is the derivative of x
squared we bring the 2 in front and it
just gives us 2X and then we're going to
subtract and what is the derivative of x
times y well the function X is being
multiplied by the function y so we have
to use product rule so it's going to be
the derivative of x times y plus x times
the derivative of y and then what is the
derivative of 25 that's equal to zero so
this is our next step so from here we
clean up these primes X Prime is the
derivative of x which is one and Y Prime
is the derivative of y if we write that
as d y d x that's the thing we're trying
to solve for next we can distribute the
negative to both of these terms they're
both going to become negative so our
goal is to get dydx alone so let's move
all the terms that don't have a d y d x
to the other side of the equation we're
doing that by subtracting this one and
adding this one on the left hand side
we're just left with the negative x d y
d x and on the right hand side we have
the negative 2x plus y from here we can
divide both sides by negative X the
left-hand side just has the dydx which
is what we wanted to get alone and the
right hand side is basically going to
look just like this but these two
negatives will cancel and this will
become a negative so it looks like this
2x minus y over X